## **NEIL SMITH**

Address: Winchester, SO22 4ES, UK Email: neilcsmith21@gmail.com

**Phone number:** +44 7599413676 **Web:** https://neils-website.azurewebsites.net



## **SUMMARY**

Software Developer with 4 years of experience working on both front-end and back-end applications, mainly using Angular and Java. Experienced with improving app performance and responsiveness using change detection and handling events including APIs. Reduced build pipeline times and risk of downtime and removing dependence on external websites. Written unit tests in Jasmine and Karma and Junit and reduced time taken to run unit tests and created unit test standards and documentation and coached other developers on writing unit tests. Published programming articles in a publication on Medium and released a course on Udemy. Currently looking for contract opportunities, available immediately.



## **SKILLS**

JavaScript   3.00 Year	HTML   2.5 Year	SCSS   2.5 Year
Angular 9   2.00 Year	TypeScript   2.00 Year	Jasmine   1.25 Year
Git   3.00 Year	Agile   2.25 Year	Azure DevOps   1.00 Year
<b>Java 8</b>   1.50 Year	Python   1.00 Year	Docker   0.50 Year
JUnit   1.50 Year	Maven   1.50 Year	<b>NPM</b>   3.00 Year



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

06/2020 - 03/2021 Remote

## Angular Developer The Just Brand

- Angular 9, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS, Jasmine, Karma, NPM, Git, Agile, HighCharts, Azure DevOps, ng-select, rxjs, flatpickr, immutable.js, lodash, eslint, stylelint
- Improved user experience and UI responsiveness by using the on-push change detection strategy and detaching the change detector, reducing unnecessary loading.
- Reduced build pipeline time and risk of downtime by caching dependencies during pipeline, removing dependence on external websites.
- Reduced risk of downtime and code quality by adding build validation policies, requiring unit tests and syntax checker to pass before merging PRs.

- Reduced pipeline time, by running unit tests in parallel over multiple CPU cores and cleaning up CSS after running tests, preventing memory leaks.
- Improved code quality and prevented code coverage dropping by ensuring PR
  pipeline fails if unit tests have not been written for new and changed code.
- Improved team coding and unit test standards by writing coding, syntax and unit test guideline documentation and coaching the team on standards.
- Improved tracking of code coverage and test results, by publishing test results and code coverage during build pipeline.
- Improved code syntax and quality by migrating from old syntax checker TSLint to new ESLint, adding new syntax rules and enabling syntax checker for CSS files.
- Helped increase code coverage by 40% by writing over 600 unit tests. Improved code readability and data flow by adding missing data types.
- Improved code quality, readability and data flow and reduced risk of cyclic dependencies by refactoring code, splitting up monolithic service into smaller services.
- Improved app security by creating a service to check no personal information is saved to local storage.
- Improved compatibility of application with older browsers like IE11 using polyfills and created workarounds for IE11 bugs.

09/2018 - 03/2020 Hursley, UK

## Full Stack Developer IBM CIC

- Java 8, Junit, Maven, Angular.js, Angular 7, HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
  Jasmine, Karma, NPM, React Native, Redux, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes,
  Conductor, Git, Agile, AWS Lambda, Python
- Migrated existing UI to Angular 7 and developed a new prototype UI in Angular framework to demo potential new features.
- Experimented with new ideas and designs and investigated how new technologies could be utilised.
- Created a prototype mobile app in React Native with MongoDB for client in 3 months.
- Orchestrated the running of Docker containers along with Java application using Netflix Conductor
- Supervised new team members and got them up to speed on project and processes.
- Worked closely with business analysts and consulted regularly with client on project status, new proposals and technical and design issues.

06/2017 - 08/2017 Sheffield

# Research Student The University Of Sheffield

- Won scholarship of £1080 to complete research over summer as part of Sheffield Undergraduate Research Experience.
- Created numerical algorithm in MATLAB that finds mathematical expressions, Bell Inequalities, that can help to determine whether particles are quantum entangled.
   Discovered new Bell Inequalities and contributed original research.
- Presented research at the Sheffield Undergraduate Research Experience SURE and the British Conference of Undergraduate Research BCUR.



#### **EDUCATION**

2018

Sheffield, UK

2014

Huddersfield, UK

2012 Holmfirth, UK

## MPhys Theoretical Physics | 1<sup>st</sup> Class The University Of Sheffield

Calculation Of Tight Bell Inequalities Through Robustness

#### A Levels

#### **Greenhead College**

Physics: A, Maths: A, Chemistry: A, General Studies: D, AS Further Maths: A, AS Computing: A

#### **GCSEs**

#### **Holmfirth High School**

Physics: A, Maths: A, FSMQ Additional Maths: A, Chemistry: A, Biology: A, Statistics: B, ICT Distinction, English Language: B, English Literature: B, Geology: A, Spanish: A, Religious Studies: A



## **AWARDS**

## 2018 | Tim Richardson Memorial Prize | £150

Demonstration of determination and resilience in order to fulfil academic potential.

## 2017 | SURE Scholarship | £1080

Awarded one of a limited number of funded research scholarships to complete a research project in Physics over summer.

## **2016 | Ifor Austin Prize | £80**

The best performance by a physics student in their second year.

## 2015 | Ede And Ravenscroft Prize | £71.42

One of seven of the best overall performances by a student in the faculty of science in their first year.

## 2015 | Fiddes Prize | £50

The best performance by a physics student in their first year.



## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Published Programming Articles In A Publication**

 $\underline{https://javascript.plainenglish.io/9-html-template-unit-tests-to-write-for-angular-apps-f1970b2cda4e}$ 

#### **Published A Programming Course On Udemy**

https://www.udemy.com/course/unit-testing-angular-9-with-jasmine-html-templates/

#### Created My Own App In React Native

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.repayme

#### Published My Own NPM Package

https://www.npmjs.com/package/angular-templates-code-coverage